<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nonparametric Bayes on The MBLog</title>
    <link>/tags/nonparametric-bayes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nonparametric Bayes on The MBLog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 11:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/nonparametric-bayes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SBGLM: Sparse Bayes Generalized Linear Models</title>
      <link>/2018/12/20/sbglm-sparse-bayes-generalized-linear-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/20/sbglm-sparse-bayes-generalized-linear-models/</guid>
      <description>Hey! I’ve just released a package on Github called SBGLM, which stands for Sparse Bayes Generalized Linear Models. The purpose of this package is mainly a way to store a lot of code that I have rotting in my laptop, which I think is relevant and useful. The models will follow the Bayesian tradition of the “spike-and-slab” prior for sparsity (Mitchell and Beauchamp 1988), so do not expect to see the so called “Bayesian Lasso” here because it doesn’t work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Qualifying Course Reports: Term 1</title>
      <link>/2018/12/09/phd-qualifying-course-reports-term-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 19:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/09/phd-qualifying-course-reports-term-1/</guid>
      <description>It’s crazy how fast this first term went by! But I loved it. The Department of Statistics at UBC is insanely awesome. The people are the best, from students to faculty and staff. The academic environment is very stimulating, especially in my area of interest, with lots of active reading groups and frequent seminars related to Bayesian Statistics, Probabilistic Models and Statistical Learning. We even had the privilege of attending a talk by the expert in Hamiltonian Monte Carlo Michael Betancourt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>