<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on The MBLog</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on The MBLog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 17:40:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BIDC: Bayesian Inference for Default Correlations</title>
      <link>/2018/12/07/bidc-bayesian-inference-for-default-correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 17:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/07/bidc-bayesian-inference-for-default-correlations/</guid>
      <description>I just released a package on Github called BIDC, which stands for Bayesian Inference for Default Correlations. I started working on this together with my colleague Victor Medina back when I was a financial stability analyst at the Superintendency of Banks and Financial Institutions in Chile. In fact, you can see the slides from our presentation at the 2017 version of SBIF conference here.
Description BIDC is a package that aims to provide multiple tools for performing Bayesian inference on the default correlation of a given portfolio, along with any other latent factor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Fourier series in 2D and 3D</title>
      <link>/2018/03/09/visualizing-fourier-series-in-2d-and-3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 15:05:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/09/visualizing-fourier-series-in-2d-and-3d/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will give a brief description of real valued Fourier series in higher dimensions, with some neat plots. I started reading about Fourier series because in the 1D case they are useful for extracting periodic patterns from time series data. However, I ended up fascinated by the pretty pictures one could get by plotting random 2D series, or by the periodic videos made by “walking” along a 3D space “painted”&amp;quot; with a Fourier series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying payments with linear programming</title>
      <link>/2018/02/09/simplifying-payments-with-linear-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 17:40:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/09/simplifying-payments-with-linear-programming/</guid>
      <description>Update: I have built a demo webapp implementing the solution presented here. You should try it!
Imagine you have a group of $n$ friends and that you regularly go out for drinks with them (say, a couple of times a week). At each of these meetings, a different member of the group pays for the bill, but you keep track of who consumed what (by using one of these popular apps, for example).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>